bosch-do-it.com 2017-10-24

# Bosch Power Tools Privacy Statement

Bosch Power Tools Privacy Statement
Robert Bosch Limited Power Tools (referred to below as "Bosch Power Tools" or "we")
would like to thank you for using our websites and mobile applications and for your
interest in our company and products.
1. Bosch Power Tools respects your privacy
        1.1 For us, the protection of your privacy during the processing of personal data and
        the security of all commercial data are important matters, which we take into account
        in our business processes. We treat personal data collected when you use our websites
        and mobile applications as confidential and process it solely in accordance with
        statutory provisions.
        1.2 Data protection and information security form an integral part of our company
        policy.
2. Collection and processing of personal data
        2.1 Personal data is detailed information concerning the personal or material
        circumstances of an identified or identifiable individual, for example, names, postal
        addresses, phone numbers, e-mail addresses, photos or other information about an
        identified or identifiable person.
        2.2 We collect process and use personal data (including IP addresses) only if there is a
        legal basis for doing so, or if you have declared your consent to the aforementioned
        parameters, for example, as part of registration, a survey, a post in a Bosch Power
        Tools Community, or a competition, or for the purposes of contract performance.
3. Intended purpose
        Bosch Power Tools or a service company authorised by Bosch Power Tools uses your
        personal data for the purposes of technical administration of websites and mobile
        applications, and for customer management, product surveys and your enquiries to
        Bosch Power Tools, only to the extent necessary in each case.
4. Transmission of data to third parties
        Bosch Power Tools has engaged the services of external providers for functions such
        as sales and marketing services, contract management, payment processing,
        programming, data hosting and hotline services. Bosch Power Tools has selected these
        service providers with care and monitors them on a regular basis, particularly with
        regard to the careful handling and safeguarding of the data they store. All the service
        providers are required by Bosch Power Tools to maintain confidentiality and comply
        with statutory requirements.

5. Use of cookies
       5.1 General
       Cookies are small text files which are stored on your computer. These files are used to
       determine whether your terminal device has already communicated with our sites. By
       reading the cookie data we can design our websites to suit you and make them easier
       for you to use.
       5.2 Bosch Power Tools cookies
       Bosch Power Tools uses cookies and active components (such as JavaScript) to keep
       track of visitors’ preferences and optimise the design of the websites accordingly.
       5.3 Third-party providers’ cookies
       Content and services from other providers (e.g. YouTube, Facebook and Twitter),
       which may use cookies and active components, are integrated into some Bosch Power
       Tools websites. Bosch Power Tools has no control over how these providers process
       personal data.
       5.4 Disabling and deleting cookies
       Whenever you visit our websites, you are asked in a cookie-layer pop-up whether you
       want to allow the cookies used on our site or disable them in the settings.
       If you decide not to allow cookies, an opt-out cookie is set in your browser. This
       cookie is used solely to record your objection. However, if you disable cookies some
       functions of our websites may no longer be available to you. Please be aware that for
       technical reasons an opt-out cookie can be used only for the browser by which it was
       set. If you delete the cookies or use a different browser or terminal device, you need to
       repeat the opt-out procedure.
       On the other hand, the settings option does not cover the cookies set by other providers
       when you visit third-party websites.
       However, you can delete all cookies at any time via your browser. Please refer to the
       help functions in your browser for information. However, if you do delete cookies,
       some functions may no longer be available to you.
       In addition, the following website allows you to manage and deactivate the use of
       cookies by third-party providers:
       http://www.youronlinechoices.com/de/praferenzmanagement
       This website is not operated by us, and we are therefore not responsible for it and have
       no control over its content and availability.
6. Use of retargeting tools
       6.1 We use retargeting technology to optimise our online marketing and design a more
       interesting Internet offer for you, tailored to your needs.
       6.2 By using cookies, which store information about your interest in our products and
       services, and by analysing your usage patterns, we can provide you with personalised
       and interest-based advertising on the websites of our retargeting partners, such as
       Google AdWords. This is, however, done in anonymised form so that you cannot be
       identified via retargeting.
       6.3 If you do not want Bosch Power Tools and its retargeting partners to use the
       retargeting cookies in question, please follow the instructions in section 5.4.

7. Use of conversion tracking
       7.1 We use the so called conversion Tracking to design our online offers as attractive
       as possible for our users.
       7.2 Within this analysis service our conversion tracking partners such as Google
       AdWords place a cookie on your computer (“conversion cookie”), given that you
       reached our website via an ad of the particular partner. Those Cookies expire after 30
       days. If you visit specific websites of us and the cookie has not yet expired, us and the
       particular conversion tracking partner can see, that someone clicked on the ad and
       because of that has been directed to our website. The cookies cannot be traced back
       via our website. The information that is collected via the conversion cookie serves to
       create conversion statistics and to find out the total number of users that has been
       clicking on the particular ad and that has been directed to a website which has been
       provided with a conversion tracking tag.
       This is, however, done in anonymised form so that you cannot be identified via the
       conversion tracking.
       7.3 If you do not want Bosch Power Tools and its conversion tracking partners to use
       the conversion cookies in question, please follow the instructions in section 5.4.
8. Use of analysis tools
       8.1 Bosch Power Tools measures website access using web analysis tools such as
       WebTrends.
       8.2 When selecting analysis tools, we take care to ensure that they capture access data
       only in anonymised form so that no link can be established to a user. In particular, this
       is achieved by anonymising the IP address. Cookies are used for measuring purposes
       so that website usage can be analysed. In particular, this allows Bosch Power Tools to
       improve data quality. The information derived on usage of the websites is sent to the
       statistics server (wts.bosch.com) operated by Bosch Power Tools in Germany. Only
       authorised persons are granted access to this anonymised data.
       8.3 If you do not want the analysis cookies in question to be used, please follow the
       instructions in section 5.4.
9. Use of social plug-ins
       9.1 On its websites and mobile applications, Bosch Power Tools uses features known
       as social plug-ins for social networks such as Facebook, Twitter and Google+. These
       are buttons such as the Facebook Like button.
       9.2 By using what is known as the 2-click method, we prevent your visit to our
       websites from being recorded and analysed by default by providers of social networks.
       When you access one of our website pages which contains plug-ins like these, they are
       initially deactivated. They are activated only when you click the button provided. By
       activating a plug-in you create the link to the social network in question and give your
       consent to the transmission of your data. When you click the relevant button, the
       appropriate information is transmitted directly from your browser to the social

       network concerned, where it is stored. If you want to put a stop to transmission, you
       need to deactivate the plug-in again.
       9.3 If you are logged into a social network, it can also associate the visit with your
       account on that network. If you do not want the social network in question to link the
       data gathered during your visit with your stored membership details, you need to log
       out of the network in question before clicking the social plug-in button.
       9.4 Please refer to the relevant social network’s data protection notice for information
       about the purpose and scope of the collection, further processing and use of data by the
       social network, as well as your associated rights and the settings options for protecting
       your privacy.
10. Use of registration services
       10.1 We give you the option of registering on our websites and mobile applications
       using social logins such as Facebook Connect.
       10.2 In order to register, you will be directed to the relevant social network service’s
       site, where you can sign up using your locally held data. Consequently, your account
       on the network in question will be linked to our service. When the link is established,
       given your consent, the information in your public profile held on that network, your
       e-mail address and the identification tags of your social network-friends will be
       transmitted to us by the concerned social network service.
       Conversely, the social network service used for registration receives your login status,
       browser information and your IP address, if you declare your consent to this when you
       visit our website.
       10.3 If you do not want data to be transmitted between us and the social network
       services, you should use our own registration services to sign up instead of those on
       the social networks.
11. Advertising
       11.1 Giving and revoking consent
       We use any personal data you give us to inform you about our products and services
       and, if applicable, to ask you questions about them, provided that you have given us
       your express consent to use your personal data for advertising purposes. If we use a
       market research institute to conduct a poll, it will operate solely under contract and in
       accordance with instructions from Bosch Power Tools.
       If you have given us your consent to use the data for advertising, but in the future find
       that you no longer wish to receive advertising from Bosch Power Tools, you can
       withdraw your consent in future at any time. Your data will then be deleted
       accordingly or, if still needed for billing and accounting purposes, blocked.
       11.2 Newsletters
       Where appropriate, our websites and applications allow you to subscribe to
       newsletters. For this we use what is known as a double opt-in process, whereby we
       will send you a newsletter by e-mail, mobile messaging services (e.g. WhatsApp), text
       messages or push notifications only if you have first of all given us specific
       confirmation, by clicking a link in a notification, that the newsletter service is to be
       activated. Should you later decide that you do not want to receive newsletters, you can

       cancel the subscription at any time by revoking your consent. The revocation of the
       consent takes place for e-mail newsletter via the link mentioned in the newsletter, via
       e-mail to the service agent or in the management settings of the respective website. For
       mobile newsletters the revocation takes places by sending a message saying “stop” to
       the particular provider.
       11.3 Competitions
       If you take part in one of Bosch Power Tools’ competitions, we use your data to notify
       you if you win and for the purpose of advertising our products, if you have given us
       your consent to do so. You can find detailed information about competitions in the
       associated terms and conditions of participation, if applicable.
12. Bosch Power Tools Communities
       12.1 We give you the opportunity to become a member of one of our Bosch Power
       Tools Communities (such as the Bob Community, 1-2-do-Community, Dremel DIY
       Forum). There you can register, create a user profile and communicate with other
       members. We use the data you generate there only within the scope of your consent
       you declare at this point for the concerned purposes of marketing, market research and
       service.
       12.2 Via an input mask in the particular community you have the possibility to choose,
       whether specific information of your user profile is to be published to all the members
       of the community or only to your “community-friends” or to remain private. All the
       other data that you generate within the communities, for example by creating
       comments or images, however is publically available and linked to your user profile.
13. Online-Shops creditworthiness evaluation
            1. To pre-empt payment problems we conduct creditworthiness evaluations. For
                this we commissioned
                Adyen BV
                Simon Carmiggeltstraat 6-50
                1011 DJ Amsterdam
                Netherlands
                as payment service provider. This service provider carries out a suitable
                assessment using mathematical and statistical methods, then supplies us with
                information regarding the likelihood of payment default. If you choose the
                method of payment “buy on account” your address will be part of the
                evaluation process. Each customer is offered the same methods of payment, the
                evaluation takes place only after you have placed your order. Should you not
                agree with the result of the evaluation, you can let us know in writing so that
                we can reconsider our decision. Furthermore you have a right to information
                towards the aforementioned service provider regarding the relevant reasons for
                the decision.

14. Mobile applications
       14.1 Use of our mobile applications
       In addition to our online offer, we can provide you with mobile applications which
       you can download to your mobile device. You have the rights specified here for these
       applications as well. In addition to the data collected on websites, our mobile
       applications collect further items of personal data which result specifically from the
       use of a mobile device. However, this happens only if you have given us your consent
       to do so in each case.
       14.2 Collection of your location data
       Our offer also includes location-based services, which allow us to provide you with
       specific offers tailored to your particular location. In order to offer you these functions
       of the app, we collect your location data via GPS and your IP address, subject to your
       consent. You can permit or revoke this function at any time using the settings of the
       app in question or your operating system.
       Your location is then transmitted to us at regular intervals, though in each case we use
       only your last three notified locations and delete any previous location notifications. If
       location collection is active, this is shown on the status bar of your terminal device.
       Your location data is not used to create movement profiles beyond your current
       location.
       14.3 Collection of your Advertising Identifier/Advertising ID
       For the purpose of advertising, given your consent, we use for iOS the so called
       “Advertising Identifier” (IDFA) and for Android the so called “Advertising ID”. These
       are singular, but non-personalized and not permanent identification numbers for a
       particular end device, which is provided by iOS or Android. This collected data is not
       being linked to any other device-related information. We use the identification
       numbers only to provide you with customized commercials and to evaluate your
       usage. If you activate the option “no Ad-Tracking” in the iOS settings in “privacy” –
       “advertising”, or in Android choose the option “opt out of interest-based ads” under
       “Google Settings” under “ Ads”, we can only conduct the following measures:
       measurement of your interaction with banners by counting the number of displays of a
       banner without being clicked on (“frequency capping”), click rate, detection of unique
       usage (“unique user”) and security measures, anit-fraud and elimination of errors. You
       can delete the IDFA or the Advertising ID in your device settings at any time (“set
       back Ad-ID”), then a new identification number will be created, which is not being
       linked to the previously collected data. We point out that it is possible that you might
       not be able to use all the functions of our App if you restrict the use of the
       aforementioned identification number.
       14.4 Data transmission to the app store
       When a particular application is downloaded, there is no data collection on our part
       and the transmission of data such as user name, e-mail address and individual device
       characteristics to the app store is outside our sphere of responsibility. We have no
       control over such data collection.
15. Use of external links
       Bosch Power Tools websites may contain links to websites of third-party providers
       with which we have no association. After you have clicked the link, we have no
       further control over the collection, processing and use of any of the personal data (such

        as IP address or URL of the page containing the link) transmitted to the third party
        when the link is clicked, since the conduct of third parties is clearly beyond our
        control. Bosch Power Tools assumes no responsibility for the processing of such
        personal data by third parties.
16. Security
        16.1 Our own staff and the service companies engaged by Bosch Power Tools are
        sworn to secrecy and obliged to comply with the provisions of the Data Protection Act
        1998.
        16.2 Bosch Power Tools takes all necessary technical and organisational measures as
        defined in the Data Protection Act 1998 to protect your data, when it is under our
        management, against manipulation, loss, destruction, access by unauthorised persons
        and unauthorised disclosure. Our security measures are constantly being improved in
        line with technological developments.
17. Information and corrections
        Users have the right to request information at any time concerning the personal data
        stored about them. In addition, users can ask for their data to be corrected at any time.
18. Revocation and deletion
        18.1 Furthermore, you may, at any time, revoke your consent to the collection,
        processing and use of your personal data in future.
        18.2 Personal data is deleted if you revoke your consent to it being stored, if
        knowledge of the personal data if no longer required to fulfil the aim pursued by
        storing it, or if storage is not permissible on other legal grounds.
        18.3 Data which is required for billing or accounting purposes, or is subject to
        statutory retention obligations, is unaffected. But even this data is blocked if access is
        not required.
19. Contact
        For information, corrections, suggestions and complaints regarding the processing of
        your personal data, and to revoke your consent, please contact our data security
        officer:
        Mr Peter Threadgold
        Data Security Officer
        P.O. Box 1092; Broadwater Park; North Orbital Road
        Denham
        Middlesex
        UB8 9UX

Great Britain
e-mail address: PT.DSO@BOSCH.COM
